출처 : 하비 자막 동호회
(http://havy.co.kr)
(http://havy.co.EN)
번역 : 안나
(anna6860@hotmail.com)
싱크 : 안나
1968년에..
Nineteen-sixty-eight...
난 12살이었다
I was twelve years old.
그 해엔 많은 일이 있었다
A lot happened that year.
데니스 맥레인은 31
게임을 승리로 이끌었으며
Dennis McLain won
thirty-one games...
모드 스쿠아드 (1960년대 말 히피
경찰 3총사 드라마)가 방송을 탔다
The Mod Squad" hit the air...
그리고 난 힐크레스트
초등학교를 졸업하고
And I graduated from
Hillcrest Elementary,
중학교에 입학했다
and entered junior high school.
드라마처럼 어쩌면 나도
그 변화를 잘 헤쳐나갈 것이다
But we'll get to that.
하지만 앞으로 일어날 일을
표현할 방법은 없다
There's no pretty way to put this...
난 교외에서 자랐다
I grew up in the suburbs.
사람들은 교외라면
I guess most people
think of the suburbs...
도시의 불리한 조건을
모두 갖춘 곳으로 생각할거다
As a place with all the
disadvantages of the city...
반대로 시골의 이점 또한 없는..
And none of
the advantages of the country.
And vice versa.
하지만 생각하기에 따라선..
But, in a way...
교외에서의 나날은
우리에겐 놀라운 나날들이었다
Those really were the wonder
years for us there in the suburbs.
아이들에게 있어선
황금의 시기다
It was kind of a golden
age for kids.
저기 있는 애가 바로 나다
- 케빈 아놀드, 1968년
There, that's me -
Kevin Arnold, 1968.
중학교에 입학하기 전 여름이다
The summer before
junior high school.
저리 꺼져!
Hike!
스스로 말하긴 좀 껄끄럽지만
난 꽤 상당한 운동 신경의 소유자다
And I don't mind saying
I was a pretty fair little athlete.
꽤 어려운 패스였어
It was a pretty hard pass.
글쎄.. 그래..
Well, uh...yeah
공에 역스핀이 걸렸던 거 같아
I think it had sort of
a reverse-spin on it...
케빈, 여자친구와
수다 좀 그만 떠시지
Come on Kevin, stop gabbing
with your girlfriend
얜 내 여자 친구가 아냐
She's not my girlfriend!
사실 그랬다, 위니 쿠퍼는
내 여자 친구가 아니었다
This was true. Winnie Cooper
was not my girlfriend.
어렸을 때 우린 종종..
When we were very little...
함께 어울려 하퍼 숲으로 놀러가
반딧불을 잡곤 했었지만
We used to go down to Harper's
Woods and catch fireflies.
9살 이후론 그다지 그곳에서
어울려 노는 일이 없었다
But we really hadn't hung out at
all together since we were about nine
이런, 여자 친구가
화났나 본데
Uh-oh, think
girlfriend's mad at you.
가서 안아주고
프렌치 키스라도 해주지 그래
Maybe you'd better go
give her a big French kiss.
닥쳐, 웨인!
Shut up, Wayne!
이봐, 여자들아
이쪽으로 와봐
Hey girls, come on over here.
케빈이 프렌치 키스의
진수를 보여준단다
Kevin's gonna show you
what a French kiss is! Hah-hah.
멍청이
Buttface.
뭐랬냐?
/ 아무말도!
What did you say?
/Nothing.
나와 형 웨인과의 대화는
대개 이런식으로 끝이 난다
This is the way most of
my conversations
with my brother Wayne ended.
형은 내가 태어났단 사실에
깊이 낙담했음에 틀림 없다
Apparently he just deeply regretted
the fact that I had been born,
그리고 웨인은 나도 그렇게
느끼길 바랬다
and he wanted me
to feel the same way.
그러지마, 웨인
일으켜 세워줘!
Come on Wayne, let him up!
미안하다만, 폴
이건 가족 일이라서 말이지
I'm sorry Paul,
this is a family matter.
바로 내 단짝 친구
폴 파이퍼다
That was my best friend,
Paul Pfeiffer.
폴은 모든 것에 알레르기다
Paul was allergic to everything.
웨인은 폴은 아마 자기 코딱지에도
알레르기일 거라며 놀리곤 한다
Wayne used to say he was
even allergic to his own snot.
웨인은 정말 재밌는 사람이다
Wayne was really a funny guy.
이봐! 웨인! 그만 두지 않으면
너한테도 똑같이 해 주겠어
Hey Wayne! Knock it off
Before I do the same thing to you!
위니의 오빠
브라이언 쿠퍼다
Winnie's brother, Brian Cooper.
그는 19살이며
우리에겐 '쿨가이'로 통한다
He was nineteen and for us
he defined "cool".
그는 정말 굉장한
59년형 '엘 카미노'를 가지고 있다
He had this really great...
'59 El Camino
물론 달리진 못 했지만 그는 항상
밖에 나와 차를 작동시켜 보려 했다
didn't run of course - but he was
always out there workin' on it...
땀과 기름에 절은 그 손이란..
Sweaty, grease all over his hands...
사나이중의 사나이다
What a guy.
그해 6월 그는 징병되어
베트남으로 떠났다
That June he got drafted
and packed off to Vietnam.
하지만 그의 차는 아직 집 앞
블록 위에 세워져 있다
But his car was
still out front, up on blocks...
그 차에 생명을 주려던 사람이
누구였는지 상기시켜 주려는 듯..
As kind of a reminder of who
really ran things on our street.
엄마, 폴 우리집에서
저녁 먹고 가도 돼요?
Mom, can Paul stay for dinner?!
물론이지
폴 엄마도 아신다면..
Sure, if his mom knows.
뭐 있는데?
/ 엄마, 뭐 있는데요?
What are you having?
/What are we having?!
고기 있어
Meat loaf.
나 알레르기야
I'm allergic to it.
다른 건 없어요?
What else?!
샐러드!
Salad.
오늘 메콩강 삼각주에서
심한 교전이 있었습니다
and more heavy fighting
in the Mekong delta today.
해군과 베트남 군은 몇몇 게릴라
요새를 점령한 후 파괴했습니다
Marines and South
Vietnamese troops...
Occupied and then destroyed
Several guerrilla strongholds.
사상자가 양쪽에 속출했으며
/ 아빠는 언제 오세요?
Casualties were heavy on both sides
/When's Dad coming home?
곧 오실 거야
Any minute.
교통 지옥과 일 때문에
늘 긴장하시니
And between the traffic
and his job he's liable...
아빠 화 나게 하지 말자꾸나
To be very tense
so let's not make him crazy.
아빤 늘 그러시잖아요
He's always tense.
맞아, 늘 무뚝뚝하시지
하지만 아직 미치진 않으셨잖니
That's true. He's always tense
but he's not crazy yet.
그러니 이런 평안감을
유지하도록 노력하잔 말야
So let's try to maintain
that sense of equilibrium.
왔어요, 교통은 어땠어요?
/ 그날이 그날이지
Hi hon. How's traffic?
/Traffic's traffic.
아버진 스파르타식
언어 감각을 지니셨다
Dad had a Spartan
sense of language.
카렌
Karen, honey...
너 일찍 와서 저녁 준비
돕겠다고 했잖니
You said you were gonna come
home early and help me with dinner.
제발 그냥
평화롭게 해주세요, 네?
Peace Mom, OK?
평화도 좋지, 하지만
저녁 준비 돕겠다고 했잖아
Peace is fine, but you said you
were gonna help me with dinner.
엄만 너무 많은 업보를
짓고 있어요
You have so much
bad karma in your life,
그거 알아요?
내가 엄마라면 조심 하겠어요
you know that Mom?
I'd be careful if I were you.
고맙다
늘 지켜보마
Thank you, I'll keep an eye out.
어쨌든...
In the meantime...
아빠가 오시면
화 나시게 하지 말렴
When your father gets back...
try not to make him crazy.
안녕, 폴
Hi, Paul.
아빤 늘 우리 친구들에게
'안녕' 이라고 했다
Dad always said "hi" to our friends...
하지만 그건 아빠가 가족과
이해를 도모하는 방법이었다
But it was like he had this
understanding with the family...
그는 우릴 위해 열심히 일했으며
우릴 부양하기 위해 노력했으니
He worked hard for us,
he provided for us,
아빤 그 이상의 대화를 우리와
나누고 싶지 않았던 게 분명하다
and he certainly didn't want To
have to talk to us on top of that.
나의 접근법은 아빠가 보드카
토닉을 다 마실 때까지
My approach was to not make
any sudden moves or sounds...
절대 움직이지 않고
어떤 소리도 내지 않는 것이었다
Until he'd finished that
first vodka tonic,
그리고 그때까지
and hope that nobody else...
다른 누가 그를 성나게 하지 않길
간절히 비는 것이었다
Did anything that might upset
him too much before then.
저 피임약을
복용할까 해요
I'm gonna get some
birth-control pills.
미리 알아 두시는게
좋을 것 같아서요
I thought you should know.
난 방금 들은 얘기
안 들은 걸로 하겠어!
I didn't hear what I just heard!
그렇게 그해 여름을 보냈다
And that's pretty much
how that summer went.
그게 내 순수한 어린 시절의
마지막 여름이었던 거 같다
I guess it was my last summer of
pure unadulterated childhood.
"I've looked at life"
"I've looked at life..."
"From both sides now"
"Been up and down
and still somehow"
"It's life's illusions I recall"
"I really don't know life"
"I really don't know life..."
"At all"
나의 마지막 여름밤이었다
This was it.
The last night of summer.
* Holy cow!
Holy cow!
침 흘리지 마, 알았지?
Try not to drool on it, OK?
카렌이 내가 이거 가진 걸 알면
날 죽이려 들거야
If Karen finds out I have this
she'll kill me.
폴, 어머니가 전화하셨어
Paul, your mother called.
지금 당장 집으로 오라더구나
She wants you to
come home right away.
알겠어요
OK.
그럼 버스 정류장에서 보자
Well, I guess
I'll see you at bus-stop.
그래
Yeah...
어젯밤에 꿈을 꿨는데..
Last night I had a dream that...
학교에 도착해서 보니
내가 아무 옷도 입지 않은 거야
when I got to school
I realized I had no clothes on.
정류장에서 만났을 때 네가
벌거벗고 있으면 내가 말해줄게
If you're naked when you
get to the bus-stop, I'll tell ya.
고마워
Thanks.
넌 뭘 입고 올건데?
Do you know what
you're gonna wear?
폴, 그건 나도 몰라
Paul, I have No idea.
사실 6개월 동안 난
옷장 정리를 해왔다
Actually, I'd been planning
My wardrobe for about six weeks.
설마 그걸 입고
학교 갈 생각은 아니겠지?
You're not gonna wear
that to school are you?
아뇨, 엄마
모델 일을 하게 됐거든요
No, Mom, I got a job
as a male model.
걱정 좀 하지마
괜찮아 보인다니까
Don't worry about it, you look fine.
우리 수업 시간표 좀
한번 더 보여줄래?
Let me see our class
schedule one more time.
싫어!
No!
폴은 주제 파악을
좀 해야만 했다
He was gonna have to
get a grip on himself.
여긴 중학교 버스 정류장이었고
This was the junior high bus stop.
선배들을 버티어 낼려면
And if we were gonna hold
our own with the older kids,
성숙한 척 행동해야 했던 것이다
we were gonna have to act mature.
우린 절대적으로
불리해 보였기 때문에
We seemed to have something
of a height disadvantage,
조화를 이루기 위해
최선을 다 했다
so we did out best to fit in.
저게 누구야?
Hooth that?
이 뜻밖의 행운이란..
What an incredible stroke of luck...
새로운 아이다!
A new kid...
우리보다 더 길 잃고 방황하는
방랑아가 또 있네
a helpless waif who would be
even more lost Than we were.
방랑아...
A helpless waif...
망사 스타킹에
최신 유행 부츠!
In fishnet tights,
and gogo boots!
안녕, 케빈
안녕, 폴
Hi Kevin. Hi Paul.
위니 쿠퍼?
Winnie Cooper?
그웬돌린
Gwendolyn.
더이상 위니로
불리고 싶지 않아
I don't want to be called
Winnie anymore.
내 진짜 이름은 그웬돌린이야
My real name is Gwendolyn.
이젠 반론의 여지가 없지
Well, there was no question now.
우린 미지의 영역으로
들어서고 있었던 것이다
We were entering
uncharted territory.
심지어 익숙한 친구조차 깜찍한
예복으로 위장하고 나타났으니..
Even the familiar Was cloaked
in the vestments of the devil.
중학교는 우리의
최대 관심사였던 것이다
Junior high school...
Was a whole new ball of wax.
그해 전미 학교의 절반이
그랬던 것처럼..
Like about half the schools
in the country that year,
내 학교도 로버트 F 케네디
중학교로 개명되었다
my school was being renamed
Robert F. Kennedy Junior High.
우리가 그 입구에 처음으로
발을 내딛었을 때
As we approached
Those doors for the first time...
마치 성인의 문으로
다가서는 것처럼 느껴졌다
We felt we were approaching
the portals of manhood.
홈룸 (학생 전원이 모이는
생활 지도 교실) 시간이다
Homeroom.
난 에릭 안토니오와
게일 애슬래니언 사이에 앉았다
I sat between Eric Antonio
and Gail Aslanian.
그들은 버스에서 만나서
서로를 마음에 들어했다
They had met on the bus, and
had taken a liking to each other.
사랑해
I love you.
나도..
I love you, too.
그리고 나도
너희 둘 다 사랑해
And...I love you both...
하지만 숨 쉬는데
약간 문제가 있어서 말야
But I'm having a little
trouble breathing here.
난 내 생애 최초의
성경험을 할 찰나였으며
I was about to have
my first sexual experience,
심지어 주 선수 측에도
들지 못 했다
and I wasn't even
one of the principle players.
케빈 아놀드
Kevin Arnold.
너 웨인의 동생이지?
You're Wayne's brother,
aren't you?
글쎄요
Well...
저희 엄마에 따르면..
그런 셈이죠, 하지만 제 이론으론
Well according to my mother,
yes. But, my own theory is...
고되게 살아왔겠구나
You've got a tough row
to hoe, young man...
고된 삶이었겠어
A tough row to hoe.
맞아요
Yes.
성인임을 증명하는
제일 중요한 액세서리는..
The first major accessory
of adulthood...
나만의 락커가 생겼다는 것이다
Our own lockers.
난 내 행운을 믿을 수가 없었다
I couldn't believe my good fortune.
내 락커에서 두 락커 아래가
바로 데비 아커먼의 락커였던 것이다
Two lockers down from mine
was Debbie Ackerman...
7학년 최고의 얼짱 중
한 명과 함께 라니..
One of the prime knockouts
Of the seventh grade.
다만 한 가지 문제는 있었다
There was only one problem.
찰리 맨슨의 락커가
우리 사이에 끼여있단 것이다
Charles Manson
had the locker between us.
수염 있는 7학년이라니...
A seventh-grader with a beard?
이건 중학교가 아니라
변태 쇼 관람을 하는 기분이었다
This wasn't junior high school,
it was a freak show.
제발 수염 있는
여자는 없기를..
I hoped none of the girls
would have beards.
락커 번호가 어떻게 되냐?
What's you locker combination?
글쎄, 물어봐주는 건 고마운데
Well, I, uh...
I appreciate your asking
다른 사람에게
말하면 안 된다고 했거든
but...actually they told us we're
not supposed to tell anyone else
여깄어
Here ya go.
누가 이 사실을 알게 되고 그걸
말한 게 누군지 내가 알게 되는 날엔
If anyone finds out about these...
and I know who told 'em...
누군데?
Who?
그것은 나의 유일한 시도였다
속일 수 있을지도 모른다고 느꼈다
It was my only shot.
I felt maybe I could trick him...
너! 너 말이야!
누구긴!
You...You!
That's who!
오, 그래
Oh, right.
그 당시엔 폭주족이 있었고
You have your greasers...
물론 히피족도 많았다
And in those days, of course...
You had your hippies.
사실 중학교에선..
And, in fact, in junior high school...
나의 위치는 내가 누군가에 의해
결론지어 진다기 보다
Who you are is defined less
by who you are...
옆에 앉은 사람이 누군가에 의해
좌우된다고 봐야 한다
Than by who's the person
sitting next to you.
좀 진지해져봐
A sobering thought.
즐기고 있는 것처럼 좀
보이려고 노력해봐
Try to look like you're having fun.
안녕! 너희들과 함께
앉아도 되겠니?
Hi! Do you guys
mind if I sit with you?
물론이야, 위니
Sure, Winnie.
우린 우리 길을 찾았다
그룹이 형성되고 있었던 것이다
We were on our way.
Our group was forming.
위니, 그러니까 그웬돌린은
폭탄이 아니었다
And Winnie - I mean, Gwendolyn
Was not chopped liver.
또 누가 알겠는가, 어쩌면 우린
7학년의 멋진 그룹을 형성할
Who knows...Maybe we even
had an outside chance to become..
희박한 기회나마
갖게 된 건지도 모른다
The cool seventh-grade group
몇 몇 멤버들을 더 뽑을 때까지
우리가 사람들의 주의를 끌지 않고
If we could just remain
inconspicuous...
이 상태를 계속
유지할 수만 있따면..
Until we picked up
a few more members.
이봐, 스티브
Hey Steve...
내 막내 동생과 여자 친구가
서로 알아본 모양인걸~
It looks like my baby brother And
his girlfriend have found each other.
그녀는 내 여자 친구가 아니야
She's not my girlfriend.
케빈이 그러는데
네가 아주 귀엽다더라!
He thinks you are so...cute!
난 귀엽다고 생각 안 해
I don't think she's cute.
너한테 아주 찐한 키스를
해주고 싶다던 걸
He wants to give you a big...
Wet...Kiss.
내게 말 했었지
He told me.
이 거짓말쟁이!
난 그런 말 한 적 없어!
You liar!
I never said that!
난 키스하고 싶지도 않고
좋아하지도 않는다구!
I don't want to kiss her!
I don't even like her!
학생!
Young man!
저기 게시판에 뭐라고 써져 있지? [절대 음식을 구내식당 밖으로
가져가지 말것]
What does that sign say?
어서 그 사과를 저 문 안으로 가져다
놓지 않으면 방과후 남아야 할거다
You take that apple Through that
door and you're asking for detention.
학생!
Young man!
우린 문제가 생긴 거 같구나
I think we have a problem.
그의 말이 맞았다
문제가 생긴 것이다
He was right -
there was a problem.
오, 맞아요, 사과 말이죠
/ 그래, 사과
Oh, yeah. The apple.
/That's right. The apple.
이걸 식당 안에
가져다 놓으란 거죠?
You wanted it...
Inside the cafeteria.
그래, 맞다
That's right.
그런데 지금은 식당 밖이죠
/ 그래
And now it's outside the cafeteria.
/That's right.
대화는 점점 딱딱해졌다
conversation was getting stale.
난 자신에게 물어봤다
'브라이언 쿠퍼라면...'
I asked myself
"Now, what would a guy..."
'이런 상황에 어떻게 대처했을까?'
"Like Brian Cooper do
in this situation?"
원하신다면.. 그게..
If you want, I could...
가져올게요
Get that.
케빈, 먼저 물어봐야 겠구나
Well, Kevin, perhaps
we should start by asking you...
도대체 그런 행동을 하게 된
이유가 뭔지 설명할 수 있겠니?
To explain what in God's name
moved you to do what you did.
난 말하고 싶었다
웨인이 날 챙피 줬으며..
I wanted to tell them
that Wayne embarrassed me...
애들은 날 비웃고 있었고
That the other kids were laughing,
디퍼나 선생님은 나와
힘 겨루기 게임을 했던 거라고..
that Mr. Diperna had played
power games with me...
위니가 그 모든 일을
지켜보고 있었고
That Winnie had seen
the whole thing and
그녀는 핑크 피쉬넷에 최신 유행
부츠를 신고 있었다구요
that she'd been wearing
pink fishnets and gogo boots.
저도 모르겠어요
I dunno.
'모른다구?' 할 말이
그것 뿐이야? '몰라?'
"I dunno"? That's all you
have to say? "I dunno"?
케빈
Kevin...
내가 묻고 싶은 건
The question is,
식당으로 사과를 던져서 네가
얻고자 했던 게 뭐였냐는 거야
what did you hope to achieve by
throwing an apple...into a cafeteria?
그게 아니지, 멍청하긴
No butthead,
왜 당신은 완두콩 만한 뇌를
가진건지 물어보고 싶은 건 나야
the question is why do you have
a brain the size of a baby pea?
케빈!
Kevin!
디퍼나 선생님이 묻고 계시잖니!
Mr. Diperna just
asked you a question.
식당 안으로 사과를 던져서
네가 얻고자 한게 뭐냐니까
What did you hope to achieve by
throwing that apple into the cafeteria?
세계 평화요
World peace.
케빈!
Kevin!
아무것도요
Nothing.
어쨌거나 네가 얻은 게 아무것도
없다는 건 확실한 것 같구나
Well, Kevin, that's exactly
what you did achieve - nothing.
더이상의 처벌은 없이
그냥 보내주마
Now, I'm going to let you go...
without any further punishment.
하지만 내가 널 계속
눈여겨 볼거란 걸 잊지 마라
But I want you to know...
that I'll be keeping my eye on you.
알겠니?
Do you understand that?
케빈! 알겠냐구!
Kevin!
Do you understand that?
네
Yes.
이젠 집에 데려다주마
I'd like to take him home now.
내가 12살하고도 6달 동안
아버진 날 때린 적이 없었다
In my twelve and a half years,
my father had never struck me.
하지만 웨인은 두 번
아버지한테 맞았다
But he'd given
Wayne a beating. Twice...
난 그의 눈에서 그때의
그 노기어린 표정을 감지할 수 있었다
And I recognized that
glazed look in his eyes.
게다가 난 그럴만 했으니까
Besides, maybe I deserved it.
구내 식당에서 음식을 던진 일에 대한
그럴싸한 변명거린 없었던 것이다
There really is no good excuse for
hurling food around the cafeteria.
당장 새로운 규칙을 만든다 해도
그는 알았던 것이다
He probably figured that
if he laid down the law now...
어쨌든 난 규칙을 멋어났고
그가 옳았던 것이다
I'd stay in line.
And he was probably right.
어쨌든 난 고통을
감내할 수 있었다
Anyway, I could take the pain.
난 그저 눈을 꽉 감고 그것이
웨인이라고 상상하기로 했다
I decided I'd just shut my eyes,
and imagine it was Wayne.
자, 들어가
Come on. Inside.
그때 그 일이 일어났다
And then it happened...
우리가 현관에 중간 정도
다달았을 때인 것 같다
I think we were about halfway
to the front porch.
브라이언 쿠퍼가 죽었대요
Brian Cooper was killed.
오, 맙소사
Oh, my God...
언제 그걸 아셨대니?
When did they find out?
에블린한테 전화해야 겠다
내가 할 일이 있는지 알아봐야지
I'm gonna go call Evelyn, and
see if there's anything I can do.
맙소사, 불쌍한 에블린
불쌍한 지미
Oh my God, poor Evelyn...
Poor Jim.
그날 밤 난 산책을 하기로 했다
낮은 여전히 길었고
That night I decided to go for a walk.
The days were still long and
그 당시엔 해질녘에 아이들도
자유로이 산책을 할 수 있었다
back then Kids could still
go for walks at dusk
우유팩에 유괴로 기록되는
불상사 없이..
without the fear of ending up
on a milk carton.
난 하퍼 숲 큰 오름 나무
쪽으로 내려갔다
I went down to the big
climbing tree in Harper's Woods.
그 후 몇 년이 지나도록
나조차 납득할 수 없었지만..
I didn't admit it to myself
until years later...
왠지 위니가 거기 있을지도
모른단 생각이 들었다
But in my mind was the shadow of
a thought that Winnie might be there.
그녀는 자신을 꼭 껴잡고 있었으며
앞뒤로 천천히 몸을 흠들고 있었다
She was sort of hugging herself,
and rocking slowly back and forth.
공기는 약간 냉랭했으며
스웨터도 입고 있지 않았다
There was a bit of a chill in the air
and she didn't have a sweater.
잠시 난 그녀에게
다가가기가 두려웠다
For a minute I was scared
to approach her.
무슨 말을 해야할지 몰랐다
I didn't know what to say.
그건 정말 이상한 기분이었다
I had the strangest feeling.
믿을 수가 없었다
브라이언이 죽다니..
It was impossible for me
to believe - Brian was dead.
정말 안 됐어
I'm sorry.
브라이언 일..
About Brian.
그리고 미안해
오늘 내가 했던 말..
And I'm sorry...
about what I said today.
진심이 아니었어
It wasn't true.
알아
I know.
"When a man loves a woman"
"He can't keep
his mind on nothin' else"
그건 우리 둘 모두에게
첫키스였다
"He'd change the world"
/It was the first kiss for both of us.
우린 후에 그 일에 대해
전혀 말하지 않았다
We never really talked
about it afterward.
하지만 난 그 일이 있었던
그날을 생각하고 또 생각한다
But I think about the events of
that day again and again...
어쨌든 위니도
그럴 거란 걸 안다
And somehow I know
that Winnie does too,
어떤 떠벌이가
whenever some blowhard
교외의 흥미없음을 얘기하거나
starts talking about
the anonymity of the suburbs,
TV 세대의 의식없음을
주절거릴 때마다..
or the mindlessness
of the TV-generation.
동일한 수상기 각각 그 안에서
Because we know that inside
each one of those identical boxes...
TV 현관에 주차되어 있는 다지
차나 테이블에 놓여진 흰 빵을 보며.. [주 : white-bread -
백인 중산 계급의, 흰 빵]
With its Dodge parked out front,
and its white bread on the table,
땅거미가 질 때 TV 빛이
하나씩 점멸할 때 쯤이면..
and its TV set glowing blue
in the falling dusk...
그곳엔 각자의 이야기를 지닌
사람들이 있었다
There were people with stories,
고통으로 연계되고 사랑을 위해
투쟁하는 가족들이 있었다
there were families bound together
in the pain and the struggle of love.
웃음을 선사하며 우릴
눈물 짓게 하는 순간들이 있었다
There were moments that
made us cry with laughter,
슬픔과 기쁨을 공유하는
그런 순간들이 있었다
and there were moments,
like that one, of sorrow and wonder.